死亡只是重获新生的大门
经历生生世世的轮回
总会以不同的方式重生
--埃及复活祷告
英格兰  公元1127年
英格兰  今日
木   乃   伊
美索不达米亚  文明的摇篮
现今被称为伊拉克
摩苏尔
圣地
伊拉克
亲爱的珍妮弗
调查这个墓穴遗址
圣地
北纬35.094°  东经43.555°
此致
亨利
横贯铁路施工中发现遗址
12世纪的十字军墓穴被发现
考古学教授        罗宾・约翰逊
由于伊斯兰教义中明确禁止偶像崇拜  因此在伊拉克有不少古迹
因为雕塑的原因被极端分子毁坏
横贯铁路  开始运营后名称定为“伊利莎伯线”
是英国伦敦一条建筑中的客运铁路  其兴建旨在提供频密的通勤和市郊与市中心接驳铁路
服务
美国军方驻地莱文沃思堡内设有两个军方管教机构 即军方监狱
直播  韦弗利修道院
重大新闻
美国军用飞机
美国军用飞机坠毁在教堂里
死亡之神
赛特神
我献上一具人类的躯体
降临吧
吾选之人
Setapai
这是什么
What the hell is this?
不知道
I don't know.
真见鬼
Bloody hell.
横贯铁路是全欧洲最大的建设项目
The Crossrail is the biggest construction project in Europe.
新通勤铁路需要在伦敦地下
Carving 26 miles of new commuter train tunnels
挖掘长达42公里的隧道
beneath the surface of London.
但今日  一个满是十字军骑士棺椁的墓穴
But today, an ancient tomb filled with the coffins of crusader knights...
人们总是意识不到伦敦就是一座大墓园
People don't realize that London is a giant graveyard.
是一座建在成百上千年死尸上的现代都市
A modern city built on centuries of death.
由于墓穴靠近泰晤士河
Because of the tombs proximity to the Thames...
其一半的空间被水淹没  是这样吗  博士
...half the space is flooded, is that right doctor?
还有更多的棺椁被淹没在水中
There are even more coffins submerged under water.
这座墓穴似乎是建于第二次十字军东征期间
The tomb appears to have been built during the second Crusade...
这意味着棺椁里的尸体属于
...which means it's filled with the bodies of crusader knights who invaded Egypt...
未能活着回来的入侵埃及的十字军骑士
...before returning to England.
这次发现同样接露了伦敦一段尘封的历史
It has also revealed a treasure trove of secrets about London's history.
把他们清出去
Clear them out, please.
女士们先生们  请停下你们手头的事
Ladies and gentlemen, please stop what you are doing.
火车隧道已经从北面改道
The train tunnel has been rerouted north of here.
现在由我们来接手这个现场
We are now taking control of this site.
请收好你们的工具立刻离开
Please collect your tools and gear and exit immediately.
不好意思  打扰一下
Excuse me. Excuse me.
这是我的工地  你这是在做什么
This is my site. What do you think you are doing?
把你的人撤出去  我们来接管这个现场
Evacuate your men. We'll take it from here.
你们是什么人
Who the hell are you people?
这边走  先生  非常感谢
This way, sir. Thank you very much.
往事无法永久被尘封
The past cannot remain buried forever.
在我的一生中  我发掘过不少
In my lifetime, I have unearth...
古代的秘宝
...many ancient mysteries.
最终  这座墓穴
At last, this tomb...
会接露古迹最黑暗的秘密
...reveals antiquities darkest secret.
一个被从历史中抹去
A secret erased from history...
并被时间所遗忘的秘密
...and forgotten to time.
安玛奈特公主
Princess Ahmanet.
美丽
Beautiful...
狡黠
...cunning...
无情
...and ruthless.
是埃及王位的唯一继承人
Sole heir to the throne of Egypt.
法老王国终有一天将受她冷酷无畏
The Pharaohs kingdom will one day be hers to rule...
的铁腕控制
...without mercy or fear.
而安玛奈特会被当作神来供奉
And Ahmanet would be worshipped as a living God.
但是法老有了个儿子
But Pharaoh had a son.
现在  那个男孩会继承她的命运
The boy now, would inherit her destiny.
安玛奈特明白权利不能被赠予
And Ahmanet understood power was not given...
只能被夺取
...it had to be taken.
她宣誓要复仇
Vowing revenge...
她选择拥抱邪恶
...she made a choice to embrace evil.
与赛特
Seth.
死亡之神
The God of death.
达成协议
They made a pact.
一个释放黑暗本身的协议
A pact that would unleash darkness itself.
安玛奈特重生
Ahmanet was reborn...
成为一个怪物
...a monster.
然而协议并未完成
Yet the pact was not complete.
她发誓要将恶魔以人身
She vowed to bring the demon into our world...
带到这个世界
...in the body of a mortal man.
他们将携手向人类展开复仇
Together, they would take their vengeance upon humanity.
由于她的罪孽  安玛奈特被活着制成木乃伊
For her sins, Ahmanet was mummified alive.
她的尸体被转移到远离埃及的地方
Her body carried far from Egypt.
在那里她将被囚禁于永世的黑暗之中
There she would remain, condemned to eternal darkness.
但死亡不过是条门径
But death is a doorway...
过往无法被永远尘封
...and the past cannot remain buried forever.
不走运啊  军士
Out of luck, ah Sarge?
平民都离开了
The civilians are gone.
那里全是叛乱分子
Is filled with insurgents down there.
我们也许来晚了
I guess we're too late.
我们能做到
We can do this.
哦  不  不  不  我们来得太晚了
Oh no no no! We're too late!
指挥部认为我们在离这161公里的
Command thinks we are doing advanced recon...
地方做前敌侦察呢
...a 100 miles from here.
军士  你不能到那下边去
Sarge, you are not going down there.
你说得没错  我不能这么下去  我们一起下去
You're right. I'm not. We are.
- 至少请求一次空袭  - 空袭
- At least call in an air strike. - Air Strike?
坏主意
Bad idea.
来个小规模的  也许能把他们吓跑
A little one. Just maybe they'll run off.
你觉得指挥部会知道我们在哪
You think command will know where we are.
我们会因为洗劫古董在管教营蹲20年
And then we will do 20 years in Leavenworth for looting.
我之前是怎么和你说的  我们不是强盗
Hey, what did I tell you? Hey, We are not looters.
我们是珍贵古物的解放者
We are liberators of precious antiquities.
- 没错  - 没错
- Right. - Right.
但我们根本不知道那下面有什么
But we don't even know what's down there.
圣地  圣地就是那下面的东西  宝藏
Haram. Haram is what's down there. Treasure.
不  圣地的意思是禁忌的知识
No, the translator said "Haram" means "forbidden knowledge".
像是诅咒
Like a curse.
如果是在这种地方提起来那就是宝藏的代名词
Around here that's just another word for "treasure."
而且这个家伙  这个叫亨利的家伙
And this guy, this.. Henry guy...
似乎很想要这个东西
...it seems to want it pretty bad.
那么  现在他就得付双倍的价钱
Well.. now he is gonna have to pay double.
- 上马吧  - 不  长官  我才不打算参与这件事
- Mount up. - "No, sir, I ain't going on this one."
- 什么  - 我不去
- What? - I'm not going.
维尔
Vail.
你打算怎么做  拿那玩意扎我吗
What are you going to do? "Stab me with that?"
哦  别这样
Oh no no no no.. No!
你这个疯犊子
You crazy bastard.
到最近的水源地要一天的时间呢
It's a full days ride to the nearest water!
最近的水源就在山坡下的村子里
The nearest water is right down in that village.
快来呀  维尔
Come on, Vail.
你的冒险精神哪去了
Where is your sense of adventure?
那真是太好了  尼克  真是太好了
Oh that's just great, Nick! That's just great!
快来  我们快进快出  就像我们往常那样
Come on, we slip in - slip out, just like we always do.
你这个混球
You son of a bitch!
我的老天
Oh my God!
我们要死了  我们要死了
We are gonna die.. we are gonna die!
快  快
Move! Move.
只管跑  快跑
Just run.. run run.
快  快  快走
Let's go! Go.. go!
你在逗我吗
Are you kidding me?
快进快出
"Slip in - slip out"?
这可和说好的剧本不一样
This is not what we always do!
上楼梯  快跑  跑
Stairs! Just run! Run!
快  快  快
Run! Run! Run!
手雷
Grenade!
我恨你  我恨死你了
I hate you, I hate you so much!
我就从来没想来  来这个国家
I never even wanted to come.. to this country!
让我想想  让我想想
Let me think. Just let me think.
如果有人在听的话
If anyone is listening...
这里是L-26  请求空中支援
...this is L-26, RMJ Hot!
请求向我所在位置进行精确空袭
Request dynamic precision strike at our mark!
你不会  刚刚要求向这里进行空袭把
You did not.. just called in an air strike!
没错  我要求的
Oh.. yes.. I.. did!
你要去哪  别丢下我
Where are you going? Don't leave me!
他们都是从哪冒出来的
Where do they keep coming from?
没路可逃了
There is nowhere to go!
老兄  我们要死了
Oh man we are gonna die!
拜托你 维尔  让我好好想想
Please, Vail! Let me think!
我们要因为你死在这了
We are gonna die because of you!
让我想想
Just let me think!
想什么  想什么
Think about what? Think about what?
我在想
I'm thinking...
什么
What?
我在想
I'm thinking...
你在想什么
What are you thinking?
我在想  我们可能要死在这了
I'm thinking.. we are probably gonna die here.
我就知道
I knew it!
我还活着
I am still alive!
尼克
Nick!
圣地
Haram.
我被告知你们在离这100英里以外的地方
I was told you boys were supposed to be a 100 clicks from here!
是的  长官  但是根据情报
Yes, sir! But based on intelligence...
我们有理由相信叛乱分子劫持了平民作为人质
...we had reason to believe the insurgents were holding civilian hostages.
我们必须当机立断
We had to make the call.
是等三角洲部队来  还是单枪匹马闯进去
Wait for Delta team to respond or go in alone.
事实上冲进去是莫顿军士的主意
It was Sergeant Morton's idea to go in actually!
结果发现平民早就撤离了
Only to find out that the villagers had long since evacuated.
他们走运了  我们则不然
Yeah lucky for them, not for us.
三角洲部队  到南边去
Delta, south side perimeter.
长官  当我们意识到我们闯进叛乱分子据点时
Sir, when we realized that we were at the center of the insurgents stronghold...
已经来不及了
...it was too late.
我们被发现之后  遭到猛烈攻击
We were discovered, we started taking on heavy fire.
长官  虽然维尔下士出于谦虚没有说
Well.. Sir, Corporal Vail here is too humble to admit it...
但是他冒着性命危险救了我
But he risked his life to save mine.
他是个英雄  事实上我想推荐他接受表彰
He is a hero, in fact.. I'd like to recommend him for a citation.
让我给你们说说我的剧本
Let me run another scenario of mine.
长官
Sir?
有两个隶属于远距离侦察部队的混球
One in which two assholes from long range reconnaissance...
就是你们
...that would be you...
穿过伊拉克北部  先于敌人一步
...run all over northern Iraq, just one step ahead of the enemy.
只是  你们并不是在追踪敌人
Except, instead of hunting for the enemy...
他们是在追踪古董
...you hunt for antiquities...
偷走所有能够拿得走的的东西然后将这些东西放到黑市上去卖
...stealing whatever isn't nailed down and selling it on the black market.
与此同时  这些狂热的叛乱分子
Meanwhile, these fanatical insurgents...
正试图毁坏有五千年历史的古迹
...trying to erase 5,000 years of history...
无意之中为你们掩盖了行踪  故事编得真不错
...unwillingly cover your tracks. It's a pretty good scam.
莫顿军士
Sergeant Morton!
在哪里
Where is it?
什么  什么在哪里
What? Where is what?
那个信封  那幅你从我这偷走的地图
The letter. The map you stole from me.
地图  我不知道你在说什么
Map? I do not know what you are talking about.
我怎么会
How would I...
有从你身边偷走任何东西的机会  这位
had even had the opportunity to steal anything from you, Miss...?
这位女士
Miss...
好吧  莫顿军士认为我会碍于颜面
Ok.. Sgt. Morton here thinks that I would be too embarrassed..
没办法告诉你们三天前的晚上
...to tell you that I had him in my hotel room...
在巴格达我请他去了我的旅馆房间
...3 nights ago, in Baghdad.
趁着我睡着的时候  他翻了我的东西
And whilst I was sleeping, he went through my things.
我不觉得尴尬  尼克
I'm not embarrassed, Nick.
恶心吗  当然  后悔吗  必须地
Disgusted? Yes. Regretful? Ah certainly.
但主要是被你的能力  惊艳到
But mainly just amazed, to your ability...
把人类真实的亲密行为模仿的如此形象
...to mimic all the qualities of genuine human intimacy...
虽然只有  十五秒
...if only for.. 15 seconds?
莫顿  地图藏哪了
Where is the map, Morton?
长官  我承认
Sir, I admit that...
我和哈尔西小姐在巴格达度过了美妙的一晚
...Miss Halsey and I did spend a delightful evening in Baghdad.
漫长又满足的一晚
A very long and satisfying evening...
假设她的反应是真实的
...if her reactions are to be considered sincere.
但是长官  除了美好的回忆我什么都没带走
But Sir, I left with nothing more than fond memories.
也许我第二天早上忘记和她道别了
Now, perhaps I may have neglected to say goodbye to her the next morning...
只是因为她太累了
...only because she was exhausted...
- 我不想吵醒她  - 行了
- .. and I did not want to wake her. - Ok.
可她对我体贴关心的回报呢
And the reward for my gracious consideration?
长官  如您所见  千万别得罪女人
Well Sir, as you can see "Hell hath no fury".
- 长官  - 天  快来看
- Sir. - Oh my God!
这是埃及遗迹
It's Egyptian.
这有什么奇怪的吗
Why is that unusual?
这里可是波斯湾  维尔
We are in the Persian Gulf, Vail.
也对  埃及距离这里有1600公里远因此才奇怪
Right. Egypt is a 1000 miles away so it's unusual.
放地上  快  去拿剩余装备
Put those down, hurry. Go get the rest.
好
Got it.
上校  这是一项重大发现  请你派人保护好这个村庄
Colonel, this is an significant find. I need your men to secure this village.
我们根本就不该来
We are not even supposed to be here.
我的工作是确保任何有价值的东西不会落到敌人手中
Is my job to make sure that anything of value stays out of enemy hands.
下面到底有什么我们一点也不知道
We have no idea what could be down there.
单就图坦卡蒙的墓穴来讲
The content of Tutankhamun's tomb alone...
就价值6亿5千万英镑
...were valued at 650 million pounds sterling.
明白吗
Understand?
上校  恕我直言  派几个人守着
Colonel.. if I may. With a couple shake charges...
就可以立即关闭这个洞  哈尔西小姐改天可以再来
...we could just close this hole right up, and Miss Halsey can come back another day.
- 闭嘴  - 好吧
- Shut up. - Okay.
闭嘴
Shut up
给你们两小时  然后就撤退
You got two hours, then we're moving out.
你带着他一起下去
You are getting in the hole with him.
- 他  - 我
- Him? - Me?
没错
Yep.
长官
Sir.
带好装备下去  这是命令
You gear up, that's an order.
我在外面守着  长官
I'll be right here on the road Sarge.
维尔  你也进去
Get in the damn hole, Vail!
该死
Oh man!
我现在在一个类似于前室的地方
I am in a large antechamber of some kind.
在北墙上有铭文
There is an inscription on the northern wall.
拉之连祷
The litany of Ra.
搞笑呢吗
..kidding me?
是你的错  尼克  你的错
Your fault, Nick. Your fault.
看见任何宝物了吗  尼克  反正我是没看见
Do you see any treasure here, Nick? Because I don't.
知道我看见什么了吗  一堆我带不走的塑像
Do you know what I see? I see statues that I can't carry out.
- 小点声  - 你小点声
- Keep it down. - You keep it down.
你在做什么
What are you doing?
这里绝对是墓穴
It is definitely a tomb.
那是什么  水银吗
What is that? Mercury?
是啊
Yeah.
古埃及人认为水银可以削弱恶灵
The Ancient Egyptians believed that it weakened the evil spirits.
现在人可不这么无知了  这玩意能杀人
Well now we know better. This stuff will kill you.
是啊  在它把你搞疯之后
Yeah, after it makes you crazy.
房顶淌水银
There is mercury dripping from the ceiling...
到地下的洞里
...into holes in the ground.
可能连接到
Possibly to connect the..
这是水沟系统
It's a canal system...
一路引到
...leading all the way to...
开大灯
Get the lights!
天啊
Oh my God.
把包里的东西都拿出来
Get everything out of the bags.
我怎么说的来着
What did I tell you?
尼克  好多金子
That's a lot of gold, Nick.
我在一间靠近前室的人造洞穴里
I am in a large men-made cavern adjoining the antechamber.
从岩架下去有轮廓分明的阶梯
There are chiseled steps descending from the ledge.
在中心还有一条水沟
There is a canal at the center of them...
流入洞穴底部的一口仪式用水井  充满了水银
...that feeds a ritual well at the base, filled with mercury.
圣甲虫宝珠  带有圣甲虫标识的戒指
Beads of scarabs, scarab signal rings.
这位是来自底比斯庙的
This is a high priest of Ammon...
阿蒙大祭司
...from the temple of the Thebes.
在水井周围设立了障碍链
There is a ritual barrier chain that's around the well...
作为对入侵者的警告入侵者
...as a warning to intruders.
禁止入内
To keep people out.
没有任何关于某个人进入死后世界的描述
There isn't a single provision made for someone's journey into the underworld.
没有卡诺卜坛  沙伯替人偶
No Canopic jars, no Shabtis.
埋葬在这样的地方
To be buried in a place like this...
应该命运比死还惨
...would have been a fate worse than death.
尼克
Nick!
想都别想
Don't even think about it.
在水池周围有六位看守
There are six watchers around the well...
注视着池中心而不是池外
...facing inward instead of out.
不管这里有什么
Whatever is in there...
这些链条不是为了将它拉上来
...those chains aren't for bringing it up.
而是为了困住它
They are for holding it down.
这里不是墓穴
This is not a tomb.
是监狱
It's a prison.
利马2-6  收到请回复
Lima 2-6, come in.
收到  长官
Copy, sir.
全部撤离  未知飞机入侵
Get out now. We've got reports of boogeys inbound.
我们得走了
We gotta take off.
让格林威上校通知一下国防威胁降低局
Tell Greenway we have to notify D.T.R.A.
为什么
For what?
- 需要从开罗来的专家  - 开罗
- I need specialists from Cairo... - Cairo?
还要潜水服和防护服
...seaborn suits and shielding cuffs.
珍妮  我们没时间了  最好拿上东西赶紧走人
Jenny, we are out of time. You better grab what you can now!
看不到水池里有什么我是不会走的
I'm not leaving until I see what's in that pool.
不行  你必须走  我们马上就走
Oh you are leaving. We're leaving right now.
我大老远来可不能轻易放弃
I have not come this far just to leave without...
喂  注意点
Hey! Hey!
停火  维尔
Cease fire! Vail!
停止射击  停止射击
Cease fire! Cease fire!
它们只是蔽日蛛  都没有毒性
They are just camel spiders! They're not even poisonous!
我们能不能  快走
Can we please, leave?
- 你疯了吗  维尔  - 冷静一下
- Are you out of your mind, Vail? - Please!
你有什么毛病
What is wrong with you?
那玩意咬了我脖子
That thing bit my neck!
- 好  冷静  - 它咬了我
- Okay.. okay. - It bit me!
够了  我不管了
Enough of this! I don't care!
老子要走了  不管你们来不来  我都走
I'm leaving! With or without you! I'm leaving!
它咬了我  求你了  尼克
It bit me! Please, Nick!
我们就不能走吗
Can we please, leave?
你释放了我
YOU HAVE SET ME FREE.
我选中的男人
MY CHOSEN.
尼克
Nick!
让格林威派一队人把这东西吊出去
Tell Greenway he is gonna send a team to get this thing out of here...
否则他就得向上级解释为什么把我抛下了
...or he is gonna have to explain why he left me behind.
快去
Do it!
好
Okay.
棺椁已固定至牵引线
Climb by the man!
牵引线固定
Climb line is steady.
往九点钟方向一点
More towards your nine o'clock!
停在9米高
Holding at 30 feet.
再一点
A little more.
B点呼叫E点  我们监控到罕见的沙尘暴
Bishop to Echo. We have visual on a severe sandstorm...
朝西吹向E12区
...heading west to Echo 12.
喂
Hey!
等等  等等我  请小心点  这东西有五千年历史了
Wait.. wait.. please be careful. This is 5,000 years old.
还有60秒起飞  快行动
60 seconds! In the air! Let's go!
小心  请一定小心
Careful, careful.
快起飞
Get us off the ground now!
哈尔西  快坐下
Halsey, take a sit!
需要帮忙吗
Need some help?
不用
No.
- 对了  不客气  - 为什么这么说呢
- You are welcome by the way. - How's that?
毕竟我救了你的  不论是什么的东西
Because I saved your.. whatever it is.
本来好好地藏了五千年  直到你投了地狱火导弹在上面
That was safely hidden for 5,000 years before you dropped a hellfire missile on it.
要不是这样你可能永远都找不到
And you might have never found it otherwise.
再一次  不客气
Again.. you're welcome.
你知道那是什么吗
Do you have any idea what this is?
它的重要性
The significance of it?
在美索布达米亚的一具埃及石棺
An Egyptian sarcophagus in a tomb in Mesopotamia.
为什么你说只有十五秒
Why just say "15 seconds"?
十五秒什么
What of what?
你和格林威说我模仿了人类亲密动作的所有行为
You told Greenway that I can mimic all the qualities of human intimacy...
十五秒
...for 15 seconds.
至少  不止十五秒吧
I mean.. uh.. it was not 15 seconds.
不管持续了多久  那都不是认真的
Well, however long it lasted, it wasn't real.
我从没在感情上骗过你
I never lied to you about my feelings.
你偷走了我的地图
You stole from me.
但我真没撒谎
But I didn't lie.
除了你自己还在乎过别人吗
Do you ever think of anyone but yourself?
这具石棺有意义
This means something.
比你想象的意义更深远
Something bigger than you can imagine.
我毕生的心血
My life's work.
你还想从我手里偷走
And you were going to steal it.
你觉得这在黑市上值多少钱
How much do you think that's worth on the black market?
我是珍妮弗・哈尔西
This is Dr. Jennifer Halsey..
对一具埃及石棺进行初步分析
Conducting a preliminary analysis of an Egyptian sarcophagus...
此棺材发现于伊拉克北部的尼尼微省
...discovered in the Nineveh province, Northern Iraq.
象形文字显然是新王国时期的
The hieroglyphs are definitely New Kingdom.
看起来美尼帕特拉国王的妻子
It appears that the wife of King Menehptre...
难产而死
...died in childbirth...
留下王位唯一的继承人
...leaving a sole heir to the throne...
一位女孩
...a girl...
叫做安玛奈特
...called Ahmanet.
下士  你小子在他妈的干什么呢
Corporal, what in the living hell are you doing son?
维尔
Vail?
维尔下士
Corporal Vail?
该死
Dammit.
维尔下士  听到我说话了吗  我说你在
Corporal Vail, do you hear me talking to you? I said what are you..
维尔  冷
Vail, just...
维尔
Vail! Wow.. wow!
Vail!
天啊  维尔
Oh my God. Vail!
放下武器  快点
Drop the weapon! Drop it now!
放下
Now!
拜托  别冲动
Please.. please..
快放下
Drop it now!
- 放下枪  - 快
- Put the gun down! - Drop it!
扔下武器  快  后退
Put down the weapon! Put it down.. Back off..
停手  别开枪  这是个密封飞机
Stop! Do not shoot! This is a pressurized aircraft!
尼克
Nick.
维尔
Vail.
- 维尔  放下刀  - 维尔
- Vail, put the knife down. - Vail.
- 维尔  别过来  - 维尔
- Vail, no. - Vail!
维尔
Vail!
维尔  停  别过来  维尔  维尔
Ehy Vail! Stop! Stop! Vail.. Vail!
抱歉
I'm sorry.
飞机故障
Pan-pan-pan.
这里是编号4099
This is November 4-0-9-9.
美国C-130运输机
United States C-130 Hercules.
- 发生了什么  - 坐好系上安全带
- What's happening? - Take your sit and strap in.
- 英国大陆之上  - 英国
- ...over England. - England?
现在我也不知道发生了什么  坐好
Right now I don't know what's happening. Take your sit!
两只引擎都坏了
We lost thrust in both engines.
联系不上地面  降到3658米  距离爱丁堡机场280英里
No way to our contact. Dropping to 12,000, 280 on the EDI.
那到底是什么
What the hell is that?
往后走
Go! Go! Go!
降落伞
Parachute!
拿降落伞
我不知道怎么用
I do not know how to do this!
珍妮  你可以的  相信自己
Jenny, you can do this! You can do this!
给我你的手
Give me your hand!
哈尔西小姐
Miss Halsey
哈尔西小姐  你是否已经准备好
Miss Halsey, do you think you're up to it.
你说什么意思
I'm sorry. What?
你得来辨识尸体
We need your help identifying the body.
无名氏
UNKNOWN
维尔
Vail!
兄弟
Hey buddy.
你吓屎我了
You scared the shit out of me.
我们得谈谈  尼克
We need to talk, Nick.
发生了什么
What's happening?
你应该知道的
You know what's happening.
我死了吗
Am I dead?
死
Dead?
不  但你会希望自己死了
No. But you are gonna wish you were.
这边请
Come on this way, please.
我的天  尼克
Oh my God! Nick.
珍
Jen.
发生了什么  我在哪
What's happening? Where am I?
这里谁管事
Who's in charge here?
呼叫基地  这里是搜寻一队
Base, this is search team one.
似乎飞机残骸一直延伸
Looks like the trail of wreckage...
到森林深处4公里左右
...it's spread across 2-2,5 half miles through the forest.
正向艾尔斯福德码头驶去  待命
Coming up on the Aylestord pier now. Standby.
码头一片狼藉  似乎是机翼的一部分  涡轮发动机
The pier is a wreck. It looks like a part of the wing. A turbine.
离主要失事地点距离相隔几英里  完毕
Miles away from the primary crash site. Over.
收到  搜寻一队  收到信息
Copy, search team one. Message received.
发现一具尸体  没有明显生命体征  待命
One body found. No obvious signs of life. Standby.
伤员证实已死亡
Casualty confirmed deceased.
请求急救人员到场  完毕
Requesting attendance of ambulance personnel. Over.
收到  搜查一队
Copy, search team one.
急救人员已上路  完毕
Ambulance staff now on route. Over.
什么  这是什么鬼
What.. what the hell...?
喂  你最好过来
Hey! You better come in to...
艾伦
Allen?
你还好吗
You alright?
艾伦
Allen!
天啊
Jesus!
觉醒吧
Rise.
一架美国军用飞机今晚坠毁在萨里郡
A US military plane crash landed in Surrey this evening...
刚好与韦弗利修道院擦身而过
...just missing Waverley Abbey.
你是怎么逃出飞机的
How did you get out of that plane?
身上一点伤痕都没有
There's not a single scratch on your body.
我哪知道
Yeah.
谢谢你
Thank you.
谢什么
For what?
救了我的命
You saved my life.
换你也会这么做的
You would have done the same for me.
尼克
Nick.
听着  尼克
Listen, Nick.
有件事你应该知道
I think you should know something.
我和一群考古学家一起共事
You know I work with a group of archaeologists.
- 是的  - 因此
- Yeah. - Well...
我们建立了一个理论
...we developed this theory...
一位埃及公主被从历史中抹去了
...that an Egyptian princess had been erased from the history books...
人为抹去
...deliberately.
我们一直在寻找一个叫赛特的匕首的东西
We've been searching for something called "The dagger of Seth".
一把刀柄上有颗大宝石的仪式用刀
A ceremonial knife with a large jewel at the hilt.
赛特是埃及的死神
Seth is the Egyptian God of death.
传说刀石合一
And legend has it that the dagger and the stone, together...
能够赋予赛特形体
...had the power to give Seth physical form.
我确信它就藏在这里  欧洲的某处
I'm convinced it was hidden here, in Europe.
几世纪前被十字军偷走
Stolen by crusaders centuries ago.
我找到一张十字军骑士的手稿里面提到过这把匕首
I found reference to it in a manuscript written by a crusader knight...
手稿中暗示匕首被分为两半
that suggested the dagger was broken apart.
宝石与此骑士一同下葬
That the stone buried with this knight...
就在英国某处
...somewhere here in England.
一处我们最近在伦敦地下发现的  十字军墓穴里
A massive crusader tomb, was recently discovered under London.
相信那宝石就在那里的某处
We believe that the stone is in there somewhere.
那墓穴指引我们找到安玛奈特存在的证据
That tomb is what led us to Ahmanet.
她应该就是传说中的公主
I think she is the princess in the legend.
石棺上的象形文字说她曾弑父
The hieroglyphics said that she murdered her father.
- 弑父  - 以及她弟弟
- Murdered? - Along with his child.
她与死神达成了某种协议
She made some sort of pact with the God of death.
接着  我看到那些鸟儿
And then, when I saw those birds...
沙尘暴还是什么的之后  有大事要发生
...and that sandstorm... Whatever I mean something is happening.
而且我也不知为何你还活着
You are alive I do not know how.
你  我  走
You... I... Go...
抱歉  尼克  我们应该触怒了神灵
I'm sorry, Nick. I think we angered the Gods.
可以等我一下吗
Can you excuse me?
一会就回来
I'll be right back.
请表明身份
Identify, please.
我是珍妮弗  我找亨利
Jennifer. Get me Henry.
珍妮弗
Jennifer.
问题比我们想象的还要严重
This is a far more significant problem than we have ever imagined.
有大事要发生了  亨利  我担心他
Something is happening, Henry. I'm worried about him.
把那个军人带来伦敦  别和他再深入探讨了
Bring your soldier to London. Do not discuss anything further with him.
明白了吗
Understand?
你来这做什么
What are you doing here?
珍妮看起来挺漂亮
Jenny looks good.
- 这不是真的  - 真的很漂亮
- Ok this isn't happening. - I mean really great.
行了  快闭嘴
Ok. Really stop.
我一直觉得她能看上我
You know I always thought I had a chance with her.
- 什么  - 你为什么要插一脚
- What? - How do you squander that?
墓穴里有水银  蒸汽
There was mercury in that tomb. Vapors.
你是怎么搞砸的
How did you mess that up?
你只是我脑中的幻象
It's just in my head.
才不是
No it's not.
你开枪射了我
You shot me.
等等  等等  你
Wait. What.. wait wait wait you...
你
You...
你杀了格林威
...you stabbed Greenway.
- 我救了你  - 你杀了他
- I saved you. - You murdered him.
所以你就开枪打了我
And you shot me.
你想要杀我来着  你还要害珍妮
You tried to kill me. You even went after Jenny.
你开枪打了我  三次
You shot me. Three times.
没错
Yes.
三次啊  尼克
Three times, Nick.
第三次有点没必要了
The third one was unnecessary.
只是你吓到我了  我慌了
You freaked me out. I panicked.
我很抱歉  行吗
I'm sorry. Okay?
不行
Not okay.
看看我  看看我的脸
Look at me. Look at my face.
尼克  我被诅咒了  你和我都被诅咒了
I'm cursed Nick, and you are cursed.
只有一种办法打破诅咒
And there is only one way to break it.
完全照着她的旨意来
You're going to do exactly what she wants...
否则我们的下场会惨得多
...or this is gonna get a lot worse for both of us.
我被诅咒了是什么意思
What do you mean I'm cursed?
不好意思
Sorry.
就  让我待一会儿  谢谢
Just.. uh.. give me a minute. Thank you.
对了  你进了女厕所
You walked into the chicks bathroom by the way.
去你自己的厕所上去
Go to your own bathroom!
没错  这里是女厕所
Yes, it's the ladies room.
你说我被诅咒了是什么意思
What do you mean I'm cursed?
你以为自己是怎么在事故中幸存的
How do you think you survived the crash?
你是我选中的男人
"Setapai".
你知道这是什么意思
You know what it means.
她对你有安排  尼克
She's got plans for you, Nick.
安排
Plans?
你跑不了
You can't run away.
逃不掉的
You can't escape.
救救我
Help me!
别站路中央  傻子
Get out of the road, wanker!
尼克
Nick!
你到底在做什么
What the hell are you doing?
你是对的
I think you were right.
- 我们触犯了神灵  - 等等  什么
- We angered the Gods. - Wait.. what?
我看到了她  石棺里女人
I saw her.. the chick in the box.
- 安玛奈特  - 对
- Ahmanet? - That one.
- 尼克  - 他说我被诅咒了
- Nick... - He said I'm cursed.
- 谁说的  - 维尔
- Who said? - Vail.
- 维尔  - 我们找到的那个棺材
- Vail? - The coffin we found.
- 是石棺  - 管它呢
- Sarcophagus. - Whatever.
上面有字
There was writing on it.
是象形文字
Hieroglyphics.
珍妮  拜托  我现在没心思研究考古的行话
Jenny, respectfully, I'm not interested in archeological jargon right now.
我们从洞里拿出来的那个盒子  上面的字
The writing on the box that we took out of the hole.
是的  对不起
Yes, sorry.
那里面是什么诅咒  是的吧  是不是
There was something about a curse in there, was it there? Was it there?
尼克  你当时撞到脑袋了
Nick, you've had a concussion.
- 的确  - 还吸进了毒气
- Yes. - Toxic exposure.
那怎么解释我知道Setapai是吾之所选的意思
How does that explain that I know that "Setapai" means: "My Chosen".
- 古埃及文而已  - 古埃及文
- It's Ancient Egyptian. - Ancient Egyptian.
那我又是怎么懂古埃及文的
How do I know that?
你在中东呆了好些年
You've been in the middle east for years.
啥  才不是
What? No!
你原先听过  只是自己不记得了
You heard it.. you forgot it..
你怎么总不愿承认呢  我告诉你
Why are you backing off from this? I'm telling you.
她真的存在
She is real.
尼克
Nick.
尼克  怎么了
Nick.. what is it?
我想你才是对的
I think you're right.
我  这些都是我想象出来的
I.. This is all in my head.
你难道就不能找到那个盒子  看看里面
Can't you find the box, look inside
若是我看见里面有具3000年的人干的话
...and when I see a 3,000 years old prune in there...
- 尼克  - 再没什么诅咒了
- Nick. - ...no more curse.
别找什么石棺了  你得去看医生
You don't need a sarcophagus, you need a doctor.
我认识个人
I know someone.
伦敦的一个专家
A specialist in London.
别告诉我你也不想见识一下它
Don't tell me that you don't want to see it too.
这可是你毕生的心血  来吧  珍妮
Your life's work, come on Jenny.
我想我知道在哪
I think I know where it is.
这里是查理8-1号基地
Charlie 8-1 the base.
我们在坠机点  距韦弗利修道院北400米
We are at impact site, 400m north of Waverley Abbey.
消防员控制住火情
Firefighters control the fire...
尼克
Nick.
尼克  你去哪
Nick! Where are you going?
坠机点不是这个方向  你是要去哪
The crash isn't up that way. Where are you going?
不
No.
就是这
We are in the right place.
尼克
Nick.
Nick!
我不知道我们来这干嘛
I do not know what we're doing here.
不是这里
This isn't the right place.
就是这
Yes it is.
不  不是的
No it isn't.
主坠机点是在那边那
The main crash site it's up that way...
我们发掘到的古董也在那边
...and so is my artifact.
我们该去那才对
And that's where we are going.
怎么回事
What the hell?
我怎么
How did I..?
珍妮
Jenny?
尼克
Nick?
好吧
Ok.
好的吧
怎么了
What?
抱歉  你说啥
I'm sorry. What?
别
No.
珍妮
Jenny!
啊
Yeah?
快跑
Run!
快点  快跑
Come on! Come on!
尼克
Nick!
喂  喂
Hey! Hey!
别  别扔下我
No! No! No!
尼克  别这样
Ehy! Nick! No!
尼克
Nick!
你刚是想把我丢下吗
Were you just gonna leave me?
你看到了对吧  看到了吧
You saw that, right?
你想扔下我
You were gonna leave me!
- 你看到了  对吧  - 我又没瞎
- You saw it, right? - I can't unsee it!
咱们是要去哪
Where are we going?
离开这儿  前面有条高速路
Away from here. There's a highway up ahead.
- 你怎么知道  - 我就是知道
- How do you know? - I know.
我的天  你知道这是什么吗
Oh my God. Do you realize what this is?
是赛特之匕
It's the dagger of Seth.
她想拿这玩意直接捅穿我
She was gonna drive that thing right through me.
那块石头  不见了
The stone, it is missing.
的确  看样子她真的很生气
Yeah, it seems to have really pissed her off.
是真的
It's real.
这玩意怎么在石像里
How was in that statue?
那个石像是个圣物箱
That statue was a reliquary.
十字军用它们来藏圣物的
Crusaders have been using them to hide holy relics.
但她知道它在哪
But she knew it was there.
你是说  是她把飞机搞失事的吗  故意的吗
You are saying that she brought the plane down there? On purpose?
所以她才要引你去教堂
That's why she wanted you to come to the church.
她引我去教堂吗
She wanted me to go to the church?
是我说我要去教堂的
I told you that I wanted to go to church.
我告诉你说  我说  我想去看
I told you.. I said.. That I wanted to see...
- 我先看看那个女尸  - 看那个女尸
- I wanted to see her corpse. - See her corpse.
尼克  她在操纵你的思想
Nick she is in your head.
你说的什么话  这也  太荒谬了  我
What are you talking about? That.. that is ridiculous. Because I...
我又开回来了  开到她这儿了
I drove right back to her.
天啊她在操纵我的思想
Oh my God she is in my head.
快走  快走
Go go go go go!
把这玩意弄走
Get it off of me!
该死的
Son of a bitch!
踢到我了  踢到我的脸了
That's my face! That's my face!
对不起
Sorry!
尼克
Nick!
珍妮
Jenny?
Jenny.
尼克
Nick!
好吧
Okay.
好的
Alright.
搞死她  尼克
Get her, Nick!
揍她  狠狠揍她
Get her! Get her!
扁死她
Kick her ass!
第二阶段  快上
Phase two! Quick!
拉住她
Pull her back!
第三队  上
Delta team move!
目标已制伏
Bring the target down!
你们是什么人
Who are you?
你要带我去哪
Where are you taking me?
怎么回事
What's happening?
待着别动
Stay.
就当在自个家一样
Make yourself comfortable.
你谁啊
Who the hell are you?
我是谁
Who am I?
莫顿先生  现在最重要的问题
The more relevant question, Mr. Morton...
是  你到底是谁
...is: Who exactly are you?
理论上来说  我知道你的所有事情
In theory, I know all about you.
武装侦察兵  授勋军人
Army reconnaissance, decorated soldier...
还有这一页页报告  表明你深受道德观令人堪忧
...and page after page indicating a deep and troubling moral attitude.
知道吗  这些档案里没有真正对我有价值的东西
But you see, this file contains nothing of any real value to me.
所以我才想面对面接触你
That's why I wanted to see you face to face.
你是谁
Who are you?
我是名医生
I am a doctor.
医生
Doctor.
研究病理化学  神经外科医生  皇家学会会员
Chemical pathology, neurosurgery. Member of the Royal Society.
还是个律师
I am also a lawyer.
我是杰基尔
My name is Jekyll.
亨利・杰基尔医生
Dr. Henry Jekyll.
在这儿呢
There you are.
这些天  我算是  在专门在研究免疫学吧
This days, I specialize in immunology, perhaps.
应该算是传染性疾病
Infectious diseases perhaps.
恕我冒昧  莫顿先生  我想
I would like to, If I may, Mr. Morton...
跟你讲个故事
...to tell you a story.
是我一个病人的故事
A story about a patient of mine.
他是个一个有前途的人
A man of promise.
一个一直觉得自己完美无瑕的人
A man who believed he was beyond reproach...
直到他病倒了
...until he got ill.
起初只是有一点点小症状
The disease manifested itself in subtle ways at first.
然后越来越严重
And then it grew...
他难以压抑自己的欲望
...into an overwhelming desire...
难以熄灭心中的渴求
...an unquenchable thirst...
他想掀起混乱
...for chaos.
他想看别人痛苦
For the suffering of others.
他很幸运
He was quite fortunate.
他自己就是个医师
He himself was a physician.
如果说邪恶是一种病原体的话  这一点有待商榷
And if evil were a pathogen, to be reasoned...
那肯定会有治愈良方的
...then there must surely be a cure.
恕我冒昧  莫顿先生  我想
I would like to, If I may, Mr. Morton...
给你看点东西
...to show you something.
莫顿先生  欢迎光临Prodigium
Welcome to Prodigium, Mr. Morton.
取自拉丁文中的Monstrum Vel Prodigium
From the Latin: "Monstrum Vel Prodigium".
意思是  警惕异兽
"A warning of monsters".
抱歉这儿一团糟
Forgive the state of things.
我们没多少时间来准备宴请我们的宾客
We had very little time to prepare for our guest.
只能依靠珍妮弗提供给我们的信息行动
And only the information Jennifer provided to go on.
事实上  她是我们的人
In truth, she works for us.
这生意  确切来说也不能算是科学
It's not an exact science, this business.
这生意是
And the business being?
是犯罪  莫顿先生
Evil, Mr. Morton.
识别确定  制服目标  做完测试  然后销毁
Recognized, contained, examined, destroyed.
迄今为止  她是我们遇到的  最古老的生物
She is, by far, the most ancient we have ever encountered.
你们想对她做什么
What are you doing to her?
用水银对她进行防腐处理
Embalming her with mercury.
在零下38度时
At -38 degrees...
她血管里的水银便会凝固
...the mercury in her veins will solidify...
解剖起来就比较安全了
...and she should be safe for dissection then.
解剖吗  你说我们只是要研究她的
Dissection? You said that we'd study her.
没错  通过解剖
Yes, by dissection.
但她是之于我们不太了解的历史的活见证人
But she is a living witness to a history that we barely know.
她是个威胁  珍妮弗
She is a threat, Jennifer.
等一等  慢点  那我会怎么样
Hold on, hold on. So.. where does that leave me?
被诅咒  莫顿先生
Cursed, Mr. Morton.
这可不是普通的伤风感冒
This is not some common cold you have.
鸡汤和一晚好眠不会让你好起来
Some chicken soup and a good night sleep will not make it go away.
你是被选中
You have been selected...
承载终极魔王的躯体
...as the vessel for the ultimate evil.
而我们是唯一能够帮你的人
And we are the only ones who can rectify that.
汝命既定
YOU CANNOT CHANGE YOUR FATE.
诅书永存
THE CURSE WILL NEVER BE BROKEN.
前人既殁
MY CHOSEN ONE WAS MURDERED.
汝将替之
YOU WILL TAKE HIS PLACE.
若汝择之
BUT IF YOU CHOOSE HIM...
别去
No.
亦何杀之
WHY WERE YOU GOING TO KILL HIM?
非我本意
I WAS NOT GOING TO KILL HIM.
我本是要给他
I was going to give him...
永生
...eternal life.
让他成为神
Make it a living God.
你杀害了你父亲
You murdered your father.
我曾深爱我父亲
I loved my father...
全心全意
...with all my heart.
我只希望也得到他的爱
I only wanted his love in return.
你杀了他夫人
You killed his wife.
还有他们的孩子
Their child.
那已经是不同往昔了
They were different times.
觉醒之日即将来临
The day of the awakening will soon be upon us.
你会成为赛斯
You will become Seth.
世间一切都会臣服于你
The world will fall to your desire.
你将获得超越死亡的复生之力
You will have power of life over death.
还有我伴你左右
And you will have me.
我会成为你的王后
I will be your queen.
屈服吧
Just give in.
尼克
Nick.
尼克  醒醒
Nick, wake up.
醒醒
Wake up.
他们会杀了你
They will kill you...
像对待我之前所选之人一样
...just as they killed my chosen before you.
好痛苦
It burns.
什么
What?
好痛苦
It Burns!
别折磨她了
Stop it!
快点
她很痛苦
Stop!
停下来
Stop it!
别灌了
Stop!
真有趣
Fascinating.
我该怎么和你说呢
What was I supposed to tell you?
如果我说真有这个地方你会相信我吗
Would you even have believed me if I said that this place was real?
当亨利找上我
When Henry came to me...
因为共同利益我接受了这份工作
...I took the job because we had a common interest.
那你们在彼此利用
So you are using each other.
而现在  她在利用你
Now, she's using you.
听着
Look.
不管你会想什么
Despite what you might think...
不管我
...despite my...
多冷静
...my better judgment...
我都在乎你
...I care about you.
在你心里某个角落  努力抗争着的
Somewhere in there, fighting to get out...
是个好人
...is a good man.
这你可不知道
You don't know that.
我知道
I do.
怎么会
How?
你在飞机上救了我一命
You saved my life on that plane.
毫不犹豫就把唯一的降落伞给了我
You gave me the only parachute without hesitation.
我以为还有另一个的
I thought there was another one.
莫顿先生
Mr. Morton.
喝一杯吗
Drink?
我可能找到些线索
I think I found something.
如你所见
WHAT YOU HAVE SEEN...
你必须知道
WHAT YOU MUST KNOW...
我研究过上古之神的文字
I HAVE STUDIED THE WORD OF THE OLD GODS.
上古之神
The old Gods?
你们的语言简单至极
Your language is simple.
你真正想知道的
What you truly wish to know...
是什么凌驾于死亡面纱之上
...is what lies beyond the veil of death.
了解我的经历
To know what I have seen?
没错
Yes.
你会知道的
And you will...
当我杀死你那天
...when I kill you.
他们找到了宝石
They have found the stone.
你把我选中之人带来了这里
You brought my chosen here.
你以为他们现在会如何处置他呢
What do you think they will do with him now?
欢迎来到神与鬼怪
Welcome to a new world...
的新世界
...of Gods and monsters.
恶灵有很多称号  莫顿先生
Evil has many names, Mr. Morton.
拿赛斯来说
Take Seth, for example.
在埃及被称为死亡之神
Known to Egyptians as the God of death.
在旧约中有撒旦和路西法之说
In the Old Testament: Satan, Lucifer.
- 恶魔  - 正是
- The Devil. - Quite so.
没错  真坏  我得
Yeah. Bad.. bad.. gotta..
恶灵是徘徊在我们世界之外的影子
You see Evil is the shadow that exists just outside our world...
绞尽脑汁地想办法进入人间
...continuously searching for a way to come in...
只为拥有血肉之躯
...for a way to become flesh and blood.
要么  我们等待它成功那一天
Either.. we wait for that day to arrive...
或者我们主动出击
...or we can fight it on our own terms.
这就是为什么我遇见了你
Which brings me to you.
我吗  对了  很好  博士
Me? Yeah, great, yes.. doc.
你说过能解除我身负的诅咒  摆脱她的控制
You said that you could cure me of this curse. Get rid of it.
快开始吧  博士
So, let's do it doc.
你的计划是什么
What's your plan?
莫顿先生  这种事比较复杂
Mr. Morton, these things are complex.
是吗  我想也是
Yeah? I bet, I bet.
处理拯救人类的难题时
When one is dealing with the salvation of humanity...
必定带来一定的牺牲
...certain sacrifices must be made.
打扰了  先生
Excuse me, sir.
他们找到了
They found it.
找到什么  什么
What found.. what?
亨利
Henry.
你是要杀他吗
Are you planning on killing him?
杀他
Kill him?
- 珍妮弗  - 杀谁
- Jennifer... - Kill who?
莫顿先生是自己作死
Mr. Morton here essentially killed himself...
在他切断了束缚了安玛奈特
...when he severed the barrier chain...
法力5000年的隔离链之后
...that had kept Ahmanet power imprisoned for 5,000 years.
他被她选为完美候选人
He was chosen as her ideal candidate.
一个体格健全  天性狡猾的小偷
A thief, physically capable, compulsively devious...
并早已丧失了灵魂
...and utterly devoid of soul.
- 什么  - 什么
- What? - What?
这太疯狂了
That's insane.
你难道想把宝石与匕首合体刺死他吗
Do you want to put the stone in the dagger and stab him with it?
那匕首会让赛斯进入他的身体
The dagger will allow Seth to enter his body.
接着我们就能杀掉他
And then we obliterate it.
慢着  慢着
Wait, wait, wait.
你想故意用那匕首刺我吗
Do you want to stab me with that thing? Intentionally?
恰恰就是埃及人那是该做的
Precisely what the Egyptians should have done.
他们打断了进行中的仪式
You see, they interrupted a ritual in process...
而这样的错误
...and that is mistake we cannot...
是我们不能够再次承受的
...afford to repeat.
- 计划是什么  - 亨利
- That's the plan? - Henry...
你不能真这么做
...you can't possibly do this.
这就是你的计划吗
That's your plan?
多米诺骨牌已经开始倒下
The dominoes are already falling.
我们没有时间了
We haven't much time.
不幸的是  我们必须冒这个险
Unfortunately, it is a risk we must take.
那真是你的计划吗
That's really your plan?
你听安玛奈特说了  你的诅咒无法打破
You heard Ahmanet. Your curse cannot be broken.
真心感到抱歉  莫顿先生  不论我做什么  你都死路一条
I am truly sorry, Mr. Morton. No matter what I do, you are going to die.
没错  恶灵是一种病症
Yes, evil is a disease.
一种不断蔓延的致命感染病
A pestilent pustulant infection...
慢慢侵蚀着我们的灵魂
...borrowing its way into our souls.
世界需要一剂解药
The world needs a cure.
你可以成为那解药
You can be that cure.
停
Stop.
牺牲小我成全大我
A sacrifice for the greater good!
这我一点也不感兴趣
I'm not interested in that at all.
这样
Okay.
- 别拿  - 把注射器给我
- Don't! - Give me the injector.
不如重新冷静一下
We are just gonna take a minute...
想一个新计划
...and we are all gonna come up with a new plan.
我们得走了
We have to go.
你不知道你这是在干什么
You don't know what you are doing.
真的吗  我知道的清清楚楚
Really? I know exactly what I'm doing.
噢  我亲爱的亨利・杰基尔
Oh my dear Henry Jekyll...
要说我在谁脸上见到了撒旦的印记
...if ever I've seen Satan signature upon a face...
那必定是你的新朋友脸上
...is on that of your new friend.
嘿   拿去吧
Hey, hey hey! Take it!
快走
Now!
- 快跑  莫顿先生  - 什么
- Run, Mr. Morton. - What?
快跑
Run!
尼克  打开门
Nick! Open the door!
你不会想开门的
You don't want that.
别去  珍妮
Stop, Jenny!
回来
Stop!
我出不去  尼古拉斯  他们从不让我出去
They won't let me out, Nicholas. They never do.
发生了什么  你把水银关掉了吗
Woah woah what's happening? Did you just shut down the mercury?
皮特
Pete?
你比我年轻
You are a younger man...
但你必须学会警惕我这样的人
...but you must learn to be wary of a man like me.
是亨利想要杀你  不是我
It's not me that wants to kill you, it's Henry.
我反而更想和你合作
I have something more collaborative in mind.
和我合伙
I'm offering you a partnership.
你是恶灵化身  而我是你的好朋友埃迪・海德
You, evil incarnate. Me, your good friend, Eddie Hyde.
考虑一下
Think about it.
珍妮
Jenny!
过来
Come on.
珍妮  别去
Jenny, stop!
来啊  孩子  好好考虑
Come on, son. Think about it.
我集混沌  毁灭于一身
I am chaos, destruction.
女生们会爱死我们的
The ladies will love us.
过来
Come here.
我确实很享受你痛苦样子
I do enjoy the garments of pain.
干的好  莫顿先生  干的好
Well done, Mr. Morton. Well done.
快  我们必须摧毁这个宝石
Come on. We have to destroy the stone.
什么
What?
没有宝石  就没法进行仪式了
No stone, no ritual.
没有仪式
No ritual...
- 就没有诅咒  - 没错  我知道它在哪里
- ...No curse. - Yes. I know where it is.
- 等等  出去是哪条路  - 我不知道
- Wait, wait, which way out? - I don't know.
死亡之神
GOD OF DEATH...
将吾选之人带上前来
BRING FORTH MY CHOSEN...
召唤埃及之沙
I SUMMON THE SANDS OF EGYPT...
接受吾等
TAKE ME IN!
将他带来
DELIVER HIM TO ME!
你好
Hello?
她逃脱了  匕首在她身上
She's out! She has the dagger.
她应该是去找你了  我们也路上了
We thinks she is coming to you, so are we.
把门锁上保护好宝石
Lock your doors and secure that stone.
尼克
Nick!
尼克  我们走
Nick, let's go!
我知道宝石在哪里了
I know where the stone is!
快走
Let's go!
刚刚好险
Wow, that was intense!
跟我走
Okay, follow me.
我们在去十字军墓室的路上
We are headed to the crusader burial chamber.
我们从西北贸易通道进去  完毕
We'll make our entry through the northwest trade tunnels, over.
就看现在了  尼克
This is the moment, Nick.
光辉的时刻
This is the moment!
你说他妈没错
Yes, you are damn right.
我会拿走宝石  把你交给安玛奈特
I'm gonna taking that stone, Deliver you to Ahmanet...
我的任务就完成了
...and then my work here is done.
什么
What?
尼克
Nick?
珍妮
Jenny?
兄弟
Hey, buddy.
安玛奈特是不会让她活着的
Ahmanet is never going to let her live.
你救不了她
You can't save her.
复活吧  我的勇士们  为我效忠
ARISE, MY WARRIORS, AND SERVE ME.
不
No! Oh no!
尼克
Nick?
你不该来这里的
You shouldn't be here.
我跟着你来的
I followed you!
快走
Go go go!
还好吗
We are okay?
- 我们在哪  - 不知道
- Where are we? - I don't know.
你还好吧
Are you okay?
- 我好害怕  - 看着我
- I'm scared. - Just look at me.
我们会解决这一切的
We are gonna figure this out.
别放弃  拜托
Just, I need you to just stay with me, please.
我们会解决这一切的  只要相信我
We are gonna figure this out.. I need you to just stay with me.
别放弃  我们会想出办法的
Just stay with me. We'll think of something.
不行  珍妮
No! Jenny!
珍妮  不要
Jenny! No!
别
No!
放手
Let go!
珍妮
Jenny!
不
No!
不要自责
Don't blame yourself.
这是她命中一劫
She was always doomed.
还有比死亡更可怕的命运
There are worse fates than death.
来我身边
Come to me.
心痛
It hurts.
我懂
I know.
让我消除你的痛苦
Let me take pain away.
屈服于我
Give in to me.
屈服吧
Give in.
屈服
当一切结束
When it's over...
你会感谢我的
...you will thank me.
我保证
I promise.
抱歉了
I'm sorry.
我们之间是永远不可能的
We are just never gonna happen.
而且不是我的问题
And it's not me.
是你
It's you.
贼
Thief.
等等
Wait!
把宝石毁了
Destroy the stone...
一切都会消失
...and all is lost.
你能变成神
You will be a living God.
你会有起死回生的能力
You will have power of life over death.
屈服吧
Give it to me...
吾选之人
...my chosen.
屈服吧
Give it to me...
亲爱的
...my love.
在你内心的深处
Somewhere in there...
我知道你是个好人
...I know you're a good man.
这个世界需要解药
The world needs a cure.
你可以变成解药
You can be that cure.
为伟大事业的牺牲
A sacrifice for the greater good!
珍妮
Jenny.
醒醒
Wake up.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
我很抱歉  珍妮
I'm sorry, Jenny.
珍妮
Jenny.
珍妮  拜托快醒醒
Jenny, please wake up.
真对不起
I'm sorry.
我不知道自己在干嘛
I do not know what I'm doing.
醒醒吧
Please wake up.
珍妮
Jenny.
醒醒
Wake up, please.
珍妮  醒醒啊
Jenny, just wake up!
尼克
Nick?
Nick!
尼克
Nick.
Nick?
别过来
Stop!
别过来  拜托
Stop. Please.
我不知道自己是谁
I don't know what I am.
我不想伤害你  珍妮
I don't want to hurt you, Jenny.
你还活着
You are alive.
看到你还活着我太高兴了
I'm so glad you're alive.
尼克
Oh Nick.
你这样做是为了我吗
You did this for me?
嗯
Yes.
我犯了太多
I have made so many...
太多错误了
...many mistakes.
这次不会了
But not this time.
尤其是你
Not you.
我不想伤害你
I don't want to hurt you.
我从未想过要伤害你
I never wanted to hurt you.
你不会的
You won't.
我们没有想到这会发生吧
We didn't see this coming, did we?
他们快来了
They are coming for me.
真希望我们有更多时间
I wish we had more time.
我会找到你的
I'll find you.
再见  珍妮
Goodbye, Jenny.
你对尼克的看法是错的
You were wrong about Nick.
他牺牲他的命来救我
He gave his life to save me.
把我救回来
To bring me back.
的确  詹妮弗
Yes, Jennifer.
他找到了赎罪的方式
He found his redemption.
但代价很大
But at great cost.
他现在是个怪物
He is a monster now.
他也依旧是个人
He is also still a man.
一个好人
A good man.
也许
Perhaps.
他才刚刚获得力量
Yet it has only begun to discover his power.
现在下定论还太早了
And we cannot know which side will win out.
黑暗和光明
Between Darkness and light...
善良和邪恶之间谁输谁赢
...good or evil.
尼克
Hey, Nick.
Nick.
来到这里我真的很高兴
I'm really glad to be here.
谢谢你复活我还有这一切  尼克
I mean, thank you for bringing me back to life and everything, Nick...
但我们来这里干嘛
...but what are we even doing here?
何去何从
Where are we going?
拜托  朋友
Come on, my friend.
你冒险的精神去哪里了
Where is your sense of adventure?
该死
Oh No.
无论他身上还剩下多少人性
Whatever human part of him remains...
都会翻遍这个世界
...will search the world over...
来找一个打破诅咒的方法
...for a way to break the curse.
找到解药
To find the cure.
但邪恶从不会停止
Yet evil never rests.
而人会一如既往
And you will call to them...
被它们吸引
...always.
亨利  他用了自己的力量来阻止安玛奈特
Henry, he used his power to stop Ahmanet.
你比任何都懂他能成为我们最强大的同盟
You know more than anyone he could be our greatest ally.
也许吧
Perhaps.
有时候确实需要
Sometimes it does take a monster...
以恶制恶
...to fight a monster.